Hello, and welcome to Lesson 21 of this introduction to calculus with Wolfram U.
大家好 欢迎来到本次与沃尔夫兰大学合作的微积分入门第21课
The topic for this lesson is optimization.
本节课的主题是优化
Let’s begin with a brief overview of the lesson.
先来简单介绍一下本课的内容
We’ve learned how to find extreme values—maxima and minima—earlier on,
我们在前面已经学习了如何寻找极值--最大值和最小值
and those have been very useful in applications.
而这些在应用中已经非常有用
Now we’ve also learned that those derivatives in maxima and minima
现在我们也知道了 在最大值和最小值中的那些导数
can be used to do things like maximize profits or minimize costs,
可以用来做利润最大化或成本最小化等事情
so they have quite a few very practical uses.
所以它们有不少非常实用的用途
This lesson will continue the approach learned earlier on
本节课将延续前面学习的方法
to solve some more optimization problems.
来解决一些更多的优化问题
So it’s just a continuation of all the earlier work,
所以这只是之前所有工作的延续
but this time around, we’ll develop a way for solving optimization problems.
但这一次 我们将开发一种解决优化问题的方法
We’ll set up a set of guidelines that should help us solve these problems in a systematic way.
我们会建立一套准则 应该可以帮助我们系统地解决这些问题
Okay. Here are those guidelines.
好的 这是指导原则
Number one: make sure you understand the problem, perhaps by reading it more than once.
第一 确保自己对问题的理解 也许要多看几遍
Next make a picture to get an idea of what you need to do in the problem.
接下来做一张图来了解一下你需要做的问题
Next assign a symbol like M to the quantity that is being maximized or minimized,
接下来给被最大化或最小化的量分配一个类似 M 的符号
and of course do the same thing for all the other unknown quantities.
当然 对于所有其他未知量也要做同样的事情
Now use all the information to set up an expression for M in terms of all the other variables.
现在 根据所有其他变量 使用所有的信息来为 M 建立一个表达式
Another difficulty is that if you have multiple symbols,
另一个困难是 如果你有多个符号
then you will need to find relationships so that M is a function of just one variable x.
那么你将需要找到关系 使 M 只是一个变量 x 的函数
After all, we’re doing single-variable calculus,
毕竟 我们在做单变量微积分
so you must have just one variable x on which M depends.
所以你必须只有一个关于变量 x 的函数 M
One last thing is find the domain of f.
最后一件事是找到 f 的值域
Find out where f is defined because that will tell you the interval
找出定义 f 的地方 因为这将告诉你
on which you must find the maxima and minima.
必须在其上找到最大值和最小值的区间
For the final step, you find the absolute maximum and minimum of f
最后一步 你要找到 f 的绝对最大值和最小值
using all that you’ve learned in earlier lessons.
利用你在前面的课程中学到的所有知识
Let’s begin with an example.
举个例子
A farmer has 3,600 feet of fencing,
一个农民有3600英尺的围栏
and this farmer wants to build a rectangular field that borders a river,
而这个农夫想建一个长方形的田地 与河相邻。
but he doesn’t want to put any fencing on the side touching the river.
但他不想在触及河流的一侧设置任何围栏
The question is find the dimensions of the field that maximize the area.
本题是求面积最大的场的尺寸
Now for the first step, let’s do an animation.
现在第一步 我们来做一个动画
Here’s the area for particular values of x and y.
这里是 x 和 y 的特定值的区域
Let’s begin by starting all the way to the left over here, and let’s play the animation.
我们先从这边一直往左开始 我们来播放动画
You see over here that initially the area increases, and then it starts to drop.
你看这里 一开始面积增加 然后开始下降
In other words, your configuration can neither be too thin, nor can it be too tall.
换句话说 你选的区域既不能太薄 也不能太高
In fact, here’s a picture you have of the problem.
其实 这是问题的图片
You have the area over here depending upon x and y, the length and the width of the field.
这里的面积取决于 x 和 y 即场的长和宽
Okay. Let’s now start solving the problem.
好了 现在开始解决问题吧 我们现在开始解决问题吧
The area is going to be x times y, which is the length times the width.
面积将是 x 乘以 y 即长乘以宽
The problem is you have two variables, so you must eliminate one of them,
问题是你有两个变量 所以你必须消除其中一个
but then you know 2x + y must be the length of the fencing available—after all, y occurs only once.
但您知道 2x+y 一定是可用的围栏长度 毕竟 y 只出现一次
Replace y by an expression involving x, and then the area depends only on one variable, x.
用一个关于 x 的表达式代替 y 那么面积就只取决于一个变量 x
Now the point is that you cannot have the value of x exceeding 1,800
现在的问题是 你不能让 x 的值超过1,800
because otherwise the area would be less than 0 because that factor becomes negative.
因为如果不这样做 面积就会小于 这个系数变成了负数
So the domain of the function is from 0 to 1,800.
所以函数的域是从0到1800
Then finally, let’s use the closed interval method like I’m doing over here
最后让我们使用封闭区间法 就像我在这里做的那样
to find the critical points, and then here is the area at that value of x.
找到临界点 然后这里是值 x 的区域
Another point is that you only have a single critical point,
另一点是 你只有一个临界点
and at the end points you have either a 0 area, which makes no sense,
而在终点 你要也么有一个面积为 0 的区域 这无意义的
or you have this maximum area over here, so you have a maximum at this value of x over here.
或者在这里你有这个最大的面积 所以在这里你有一个最大的值 x
So the rectangle should be 900 feet long and 1,800 feet wide.
所以长方形应该是900英尺长 1800英尺宽
Okay. Before going on, we need to talk a little bit about absolute extreme values.
好了在继续之前 我们需要先说一下绝对极值
Earlier on, we mostly talked about local extreme values.
前面我们主要讲的是局部极值
The point is that if you have a critical number c for a function and you find that the derivative is,
关键是 如果你有一个函数的临界数 c 你发现导数是
let’s say, positive to the left of it for all values and negative to the right of it for all values,
比方说 在它的左边为正值 在它的右边为负值
then that value is actually an absolute maximum for the function.
那么这个值实际上是函数的绝对最大值
In just the same way, if you have a value c for which the derivative is
同样地 如果你有一个值 c 其导数是
negative for all values to the left and positive for all values to the right,
左边的所有数值为负 右边的所有数值为正
then you have an absolute minimum.
那么你有一个绝对最小值
That’s just a slightly more general result than the first derivative test.
这只是比第一种导数测试的结果略显笼统
We have tweaked that test slightly to find aboslute maxima and minima
我们稍微调整了这个测试 以找到绝对最大和最小值。
instead of local maxima and minima.
而不是局部最大值和最小值
As a very simple example, here’s x^2 with its derivative 2x.
作为一个非常简单的例子 这里是 x^2 及其导数 2x
You see over here that that’s the minimum, and to the left the derivative is negative,
你看这里 那是最小值 左边的导数是负数
and to the right it’s positive for all values, so you actually have an absolute minimum over here.
右边所有的值都是正数 所以这里实际上有一个绝对最小值
As an application, now let’s take up the problem of making a cylindrical can
下面看一个应用 现在我们来讨论一下制作一个能装满 1 升 的圆柱形罐头的问题
that holds 1 liter of water, and you want to find the dimensions
而你想找到的尺寸能够
that will minimize the total cost of plastic that’s used to make the can.
最大限度地降低用于制造罐头的塑料的总成本
Now if you want to minimize the cost of plastic,
现在如果你想把塑料的成本降到最低
then the best way to do that is to minimize the surface area of the can.
那么最好的办法就是尽量减少罐体的表面积
Here is the can itself.
这里是罐头本身
That’s the surface area S, the radius and the height.
那就是表面积 S 半径和高度
The formula for the area is just the area of the two sides and the two bases,
面积的计算公式只是两边和两边底的面积
so that’s the total area. Now you want to eliminate h, let’s say,
所以这就是总面积 现在你想消除 h 比方说
so remember that the volume πr^2h is 1,000.
所以记住体积 πr^2h 是 1000
After all, you have 1 liter of water, so h is 1,000/(πr^2).
毕竟 你有1升水 所以 h 是 1,000/(πr^2)
Having done that, we can now write the surface area in terms of just one variable r,
这样 我们现在可以用一个变量 r 来表示表面积
and the domain is just from 0 all the way to ∞.
而定义域只是从 0 一直到 ∞
In principle, you could have any value for r.
原则上 你可以为 r 设置任何值
Now the point is you cannot apply the closed interval method because the interval is infinite,
现在的问题是你不能应用封闭间隔法 因为间隔是无限的
so what we do is we first of all work out the critical numbers.
所以我们要做的是首先要计算出临界值
There’s just one critical number, but then you note that
只有一个临界值 但你注意到
to the left of that value you have the derivative being negative,
在该值的左边 你的导数是负的。
and to the right you have it being positive, so actually you have an absolute minimum.
而在右边你有它是正的 所以实际上你有一个绝对最小值
Okay. Now with that radius, you can work out the height using the solution above,
好了 现在有了这个半径 你就可以用上面的方法计算出高度了
this 5.41926, and that says that the radius should be approximately 5.42
这是 5.41926 说明半径应该是 5.42 左右
and the height should be approximately 10.84.
且高度应在 10.84 左右
Okay. Now a problem about distances.
好吧 现在有个关于距离的问题
You want to find the point on the parabola y^2 = 2x which is closest to the point (1, 32).
你想在抛物线 y^2=2x 上找到离点 (1，32) 最近的一点
That’s the distance formula.
这就是距离公式
You have √(x – 1)^2 + (y – 32)^2 for that point.
你有 √(x - 1)^2 + (y - 32)^2 的那个点
Because the point lies on the parabola, you have x = y^2/2 from here,
因为点位于抛物线上 所以从这里有 x=y^2/2
so you plug it back and you get a distance function.
所以你把它加回去 就能得到一个距离函数
Now I won’t worry about the square root sign. That doesn’t matter.
现在我不担心平方根符号了 那并不重要
You work out the critical numbers, and you find that it’s just one critical number.
你计算出临界值 发现只有一个临界值
If you look at the derivative, you actually see that
如果你看一下导数 实际上你会发现
the derivative is going to be negative to the left of 4 and positive to the right of 4,
导数在4的左边是负数 在4的右边是正数
so you actually have an absolute minimum.
所以你实际上有一个绝对最小值
The minimum value will occur when you are at (8, 4), and that’s the answer to the problem.
当你在 （8，4） 时 会出现最小值 这就是问题的答案
Okay. Now on to a business example.
好了 现在开始讲一个商业例子
Let’s say you have a store that sells 300 monitors a week at $200 each.
比方说 你有一家商店 每周销售300台显示器 每台200元
Now the store finds that for each $10 rebate, of course the sales go up,
现在店家发现 每返利10元销量当然就会增加
so the number of monitors increases by the number 30 in a week.
所以一周内显示器的数量会增加30个
Okay. The question is what are the demand function and the revenue function?
好的 我的问题是需求函数和收入函数是什么
You also want to find the rebate that the store should offer to maximize its revenue.
你也要找到店铺应该提供多少返利 使其收益最大化
The demand function is just the price per unit, so that’s given over here.
需求函数只是单位价格 所以在这边给出了
You have the base price 200 minus the discount that customers will get
你的基本价格是 200 减去客户将得到的折扣
depending upon how many monitors are sold.
取决于显示器的销售数量
The revenue function is just the total revenue.
收入函数只是总收入
That’s the number of items times the price per item.
那就是商品数量乘以每件商品的价格
To maximize revenue, you simply find its critical value, which is 450,
要想实现收益最大化 你只要找到它的临界值 也就是 450
and then you can actually check quite easily that you actually have
然后你就可以很容易地检查你是否真的有了
an absolute maximum at this value.
在此值上为绝对最大值
The price at this value of x is 150.
此值 x 时的价格为 150
Now the rebate should be $200, the base price, minus $150. That’s $50.
现在回扣应该是 200 元 基本价格减去 150 元那就是 50 元
Okay. Now that’s all done manually, but in the Wolfram Language,
好了 现在这些都是手动完成的 现在 所有这些都是手动完成的 但在 Wolfram 语言中
we have two functions, Maximize and Minimize, which can actually find
我们有两个函数 Maximize 和 Minimize 实际上可以发现
these absolute maxima and minima for a given range without any effort on our part.
我们可以在给定的范围内轻易地找到这些绝对最大值和最小值
For example, in the earlier case, I could use Maximize to get back
例如 在前面的案例中 我可以使用 Maximize 来返回到
just the same answer for the revenue.
只是收入的答案是一样的
You could also specify range, and we get back the answer for that range.
你也可以指定范围 我们就会得到这个范围的答案
That’s Maximize, and similarly, you could find an absolute minimum
这就是 Maximize 同样 你也可以通过使用最小化函数
by using the Minimize function.
找到一个绝对最小值
Here is a function and you want to minimize it between 0 and 2π,
这里有一个函数 你想在 0 和 2π 之间把它最小化
so you use Minimize and you get back an answer,
所以你使用最小化 然后得到一个答案
and here is a plot showing that that answer is actually correct.
而这里有一张图显示 这个答案其实是正确的
That dot over here is the point at which you have a minimum.
这边的那个点就是你的最低点
Okay. That’s the end of this lesson.
好了 这节课到此结束这就是本课的结束。
The main point is that optimization is a very important area of applied mathematics.
主要是优化是应用数学中一个非常重要的领域
A lot of people spend time just solving optimization problems.
很多人花时间只是解决优化问题
Now to solve such problems, the first point is you must try and understand what the problem is.
现在要解决这样的问题 第一点就是你必须试着去了解问题是什么
To understand the problem, you draw a picture, et cetera,
为了了解问题 你画了一幅画 等等
and make you’ve got all of it set up right before you try and solve it.
在你尝试解决它之前 让你把所有的东西都设置好
Of course, if you are in business, then optimization is particularly important
当然 如果你是做生意的 那么优化就显得尤为重要了
because you want maximize the profits,
因为你想让利润最大化
so you need some kind of quantitative way of maximizing profits.
所以你需要某种量化的方式来实现利润最大化
There are two built-in functions, Maximize and Minimize,
有两个内置函数 Maximize 和 Minimize
which are really useful for solving such problems.
这对解决此类问题确实很有用
The next lesson will talk about antiderivatives,
下节课将讲到反导数
but before you do that, do review today’s lesson.
但在这之前 请先复习一下今天的课程
It was quite a difficult lesson.
这是相当困难的一课
Make sure you understand all the steps, and then we’ll go on to antiderivatives next time.
确保你理解了所有的步骤 然后我们下一次再继续讲反导数
Thank you very much. I’ll stop over here.
谢谢您 今天讲到这里吧
翻译 彭彦鸿